World News Insights  
1-3 Minute Gist
-------------------------------------

Support LyrArc

Reader contributions keep LyrArc open for everyone

**Search, personalize, or simply browse. Follow the world around you from gist and context to insights.**

**Sign up. It's free and easy to use**  
[Create an account](https://www.lyrarc.com/users/sign_up) to personalize your feed of articles and receive a daily email summary on your topics.

###### Updated December 10

#### Top Stories

#### MRA

#### Browse Lyrarc's

#### LyrArc Insights

#### **Countries**

#### **Business**

#### **Society**

#### **Worklife Balance**

×

×

Author

Source Name

Reporting Quality

Author

Source Name

AARP AARP Bulletin ABC News AP NEWS All India Radio All India Radio Archives Ambition India 2021 American Enterprise Institute - AEI Apple Podcasts Axios BBC BBC - Future BBC - Travel BBC -Future BBC Capital BBC Food BBC Good Food BBC News BBC Reel BBC Sport BBC- Capital Best Colleges Bicycling Bloomberg.com Boris Johnson Brookings Brookings Institution Buddhist Summit April 20, 2023 Business Standard BusinessWeek Buy Side from WSJ C-SPAN C-SPAN.org CBS News CBS News Face the Nation Sunday program CBSSports.com CNBC CNN CNN Travel CNNMoney California Secretary of State Classic FM Columbia Univeristy Columbia University Libraries Committee for a Responsible Federal Budget Congressional Budget Office Council on Foreign Relations Cricbuzz Cricket World DD News DW.com Daily News Deccan Herald Deseret News Digiday ESPN.com ETEnergyworld.com Economist Economist Espresso Encyclopedia Britannica European Commission European Council FRANCE 24 Facebook Facebook Watch Fortune France 24 France Today Futbol on FanNation George Washington's Mount Vernon Presidential Library Group of 26 Scientists from Australia, France, Britain and the US Haaretz.com Harvard Gazette Hindustan Times IEA ILO IMF IMF ISRO Immigration History India Today Institut Montaigne International Monetary Fund IMF International New York Times Internet Archive- National Archive of the United States Investopedia Istoriya Ruskoi Armii JFK Library JapanGov - The Government of Japan Jewish Virtual Library Joe Biden for President: Official Campaign Website John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum Kiplinger.com Le Monde.fr London City Hall Los Angeles Times Lyrarc.com MIT News MIT Technology Review MInt MSNBC.com MarketWatch Mette Frederiksen Ministry of External Affairs, Government of India Ministry of Finance Government of India Ministry of Finance, Government of India Ministry of Jal Shakti Mumbai Live NASA's Europa Clipper NBC News NDTV-Dettol Banega Swachh India NDTV.com NHK WORLD NITI Aayog, PM's Office NPR NPR.org NYTimes.com NYTimes.com Supported by LYRARC'S MOVEMENT FOR GLOBAL LITERACY National Archives National Assessment of Educational Progress National Grid National Institutes of Health (NIH) National Master Plan Portal of India National Park Service Ne York Times New York Post New York TImes New York Times New Yrok Times New york Times Newe York Times News News Carnegie Mellon University Nikkei Asia Nikkei Asian Review ORF PBS PBS News PBS NewsHour PM's Site PMINDIA PMO POLITICO POLITICO Magazine Peter Baker Peterson Institute of International Economics Pew Research Center Pew Research Center - U.S. Politics & Policy Pew Research Center's Global Attitudes Project Pittsburgh Post-Gazette Plastic and Fossil Fuels Politico Politico PRO Poynter Premier League You Tube Presidency Project Presidency Project UC Santa Barbara Radio-Canada Raisina Dialogue 77th Session of the UN General Assembly Reuters Spiegel Online SWI swissinfo.ch San Francisco Chronicle Scientific American Scroll.in Sky Sports News Smithsonian Magazine South China Morning Post Sportstar Supreme Court Observer Sydney Ember TIME TOI The Agenda The Agenda, Politico magazine The Athletic The Atlantic The Brazilian Report The Des Moines Register The Economic Times The Economist The Financial Times The Guardian The Guardian Supported by LYRARC's WORK-LIFE BALANCE The Hindu The Hindu BL The Hindu Center The Independent The Indian Express The Japan Times The Lancet Infectious Diseases The Library of Congress The National Archives of the United States The New York Times The New Yorker The Observers - France 24 The Singju Post The Source Oglethorpe The Sunday Times The TImes The Telegraph The Times The Times & The Sunday Times The Times of India The US Library of Congress The Verge The Wall Street Journal The White House ThePrint TheQuint Times of India Times of India Blog Times of India Travel U.S. UEFA.com UK Parliament committee House of Lords UN News UNESCO UNFPA US Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration USA TODAY USDA Economic Research Service US Department 0f Agriculture United Nations Climate Change United Nations Population Fund United States Courts United States Institute of Peace VOA Voice of America WSJ WSJ Supported by LYRARC'S CLIMATE CHANGE ACTION WSJ Supported by LYRARC'S WORK-LIFE BALANCE WSJ Jan 15 2008 WZB Wall Street Journal Washington Monthly Washington Post Website of the Federal Government | Bundesregierung White House Wikipedia- CHECKED by Movement for Global Literacy Wilson Center World Economic Forum Yahoo Finance You Tube Indian Ministry of External Affairs You Tube Narendra Modi January 26, 2024 YouTube YouTube All India Radio Central Archives YouTube White House.gov YouTube Door Darshan YouTube National Constitution Center YouTube WFAA ABC News Zeit Online ZEIT ONLINE Arbeit bbc cricket.com.au dw.com dw.com Supported by Lyrarc's Climate Change Action euronews http://www.hindustantimes.com/ https://www.hindustantimes.com/ https://www.inquirer.com https://www.livemint.com https://www.thelily.com independent migrationpolicy.org mint oregonlive pv magazine USA www.narendramodi.in www.ndtv.com

Reporting Quality

\>1 \>2 \>3 \>4 \>5 \>6 \>7 \>8 \>9

INTELILINKS, LLC PRIVACY POLICY
===============================

Effective Date: March 25th, 2024

Last Updated: March 25th, 2024

This Privacy Policy describes how Intelilinks, LLC and its affiliates ("Company," "we," or "us") collect and process personal information in relation to your use of our services and website, lyrarc.com. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, your choice is to not utilize our services or website or provide personal information in connection with them. By utilizing our services and website, you agree to this Privacy Policy and expressly consent to the processing of personal information according to this Privacy Policy.

Depending on where you live, a supplemental privacy notice may also apply to you. Please follow the links and review the supplemental privacy notice describing how we process personal information for these regions. To exercise any applicable rights, please follow the instructions provided under the section "Exercising Your Rights" in the supplemental privacy notice.

·      [California](#_California_1)

·      [European Union, United Kingdom, and India](#_European_Union_and)

·      [Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)

### **1.**              **Personal Information We Collect.**

A.    Information You Choose to Give Us

§  Contact information, including name, address, city, state, zip code, and email address.

§  Information provided or accessed in connection with the services we provide, including online forms, account information, survey responses, communications with our online support team.

§  Payment information to complete purchase transactions.

B.    Information Automatically Collected by Using Our Website

§  Your device data and how you interact with our website, including IP address, browser type, and unique device identifier.

§  Cookies and similar technology. Please review the cookie technology section below for more information.

§  Usage information, including the pages or content you view and searches on our website.

**2.**    **How We Use Information We Collect**. We may process this information to:

·       Fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information. For example, if you provide your personal information to financially contribute to our services, we will use that information to process your payment. We may also save your information for these purposes. 

·       Provide, offer, support, personalize, or develop our website and services.

·       Create, maintain, customize, and secure your account with us.

·       Process your requests, purchases, transactions, and payments and prevent transactional fraud.

·       Provide you with support and respond to your inquiries, including to investigate and address your concerns and monitor and improve our responses.

·       Help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of our website, services, databases and other technology assets.

·       Test, research, analyze, and conduct product development to develop and improve our website, and related services.

·       Carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.

·       Respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations.

·       Evaluate or conduct a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us is among the assets transferred.

·       Send marketing, advertising, and other information that may be of interest to you based on your preferences.

·       Personalize, measure, and improve our advertising to you.

·       Fulfill any other use that we describe when you provide the information.

Please note that we may anonymize or reasonably deidentify your personal information so that it can no longer be reasonably associated with or used to identify you in some circumstances. We may retain and use such information for any legitimate business purpose without further notice to you or obtaining your consent, unless required by law.

**3.**    **Disclosing, Sharing, and Selling Information.**

A.    Disclosing Personal Information

We may disclose your personal information to a service provider for a business purpose. When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.

We disclose personal information as stated below:

·       with software, data analytics, cybersecurity, cloud service, consultants, financial, legal, and other similar providers that support our business.

·       with banks and credit card processors to the extent necessary for Company to deliver the services. 

·       when we believe sharing is necessary to protect our rights, preserve safety, investigate fraud or other wrongdoing.

·       when required by law, which includes complying with any court order, law, or legal process, including responding to a government or regulatory request.

·       in connection with the sale, transfer or financing of Company’s business or its assets, including a bankruptcy proceeding or to our affiliates.  

·       to enforce or apply our agreements, including for billing or collection purposes.

·       for any other purpose we disclose to you when you provide the information.

B.    Sharing Personal Information for Personalized Advertising

In this Privacy Policy, "sharing" means disclosing a consumer's personal information to third parties for cross-context behavioral advertising. "Cross-context behavioral advertising" refers to the targeting of advertising to a consumer based on the consumer's personal information obtained from the consumer’s activity across websites and applications, other than those with which the consumer intentionally interacts.  In the preceding twelve months, Company has "shared" personal information with third parties for the purposes of personalized advertising.

C.     Selling Personal Information 

In the preceding twelve months, Company has not sold personal information to any third parties and does not sell personal information pertaining to minors under the age of 16.

**4.**    **Information Security and Retention.**

We use reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security measures to protect the personal information we retain and to help ensure that it is used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless longer retention is required by law or for auditing purposes. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable laws, the volume and nature of the personal information, its purpose, and the potential risk of harm from its unauthorized use or disclosure.

**5.**    **Cookies and Tracking Technologies.**

A.    Cookies

Our websites may use “cookies” and other tracking technologies to gather information about your interactions.  This information may include demographic data, browser type, IP address, pages visited, activities conducted on the page, and the day and time of your visit. We do not currently honor “do not track” signals from a web site browser. Please refer to your computer browser help instructions for more information on cookies and other related technologies and how to manage their use. If you refuse or delete cookies, you will need to repeat the process if you use another computer or change browsers. If you refuse or delete cookies, some of the functionality of our websites could potentially be impaired.  

B.    Analytics Services

Please note that we use an analytics service, Google Analytics, to gather information about our website visits. To learn more about Google Analytics, including opting out of Google Analytics, click here  [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

C.     Web Beacons

Pages of our websites may also contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that allow us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages.  We may use this information to provide a better website user experience, and tailor our marketing communications. 

**6.**    **Your Rights.**

Depending on where you live, you may have rights related to your personal information. These rights are described in the [supplemental privacy notice](#_SUPPLEMENTAL_PRIVACY_NOTICE). You may exercise any of the rights consistent with applicable law by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and following the instructions provided in the supplemental privacy notice document, under the "[Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)" section. We may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request.

**7.**    **Other Important Information.**

A.    Linked Websites

Our websites may contain links to other websites. We assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party websites.  You expressly relieve Company from any and all liability arising from your use of any third-party website, or from the content of any third-party website.

B.    Children's Privacy

Our website does not target or knowingly collect any information from individuals under the age of 16.

C.     Changes to our Privacy Policy

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our Privacy Policy on this page with a notification that the Privacy Policy has been updated on our website home pages. If we make material changes to how we treat the personal information we collect, we will notify you through a prominent notice on our website home pages, in addition to any other means necessary to fulfill our legal requirements. The date the Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. 

**8.**    **Contact Information.**

For questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at any of the following addresses. To exercise your consumer rights, depending on where you live, please follow the instructions provided in the [supplemental privacy notice](#_SUPPLEMENTAL_PRIVACY_NOTICE), under the "[Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)" section.

Email:             [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Address:         3020 Lindenwood Dr.  
Dearborn, Michigan 48120

SUPPLEMENTAL PRIVACY NOTICE
===========================

Last Updated: March 25th, 2024

If you reside in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Nevada, Utah, Vermont, or Virginia, this page applies to you and supplements our [Privacy Policy](#_[COMPANY]_PRIVACY_NOTICE). To exercise any of the rights described below consistent with applicable law, please follow the instructions provided in the "[Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)" section of this document.

To comply with your request, we may ask that you verify your identity for security purposes before we take further action. Only you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child. To designate an authorized agent, please contact us via the methods noted above.

·      [California](#_California_1)

·      [European Union, United Kingdom, and India](#_European_Union,_United)

·      [Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)

California
----------

Last Updated: March 25th, 2024

This supplements the information contained the [Privacy Policy](#_[COMPANY]_PRIVACY_NOTICE) and applies solely to individuals who reside in the State of California. To exercise any of the rights described below consistent with applicable law, please follow the instructions provided in the "[Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)" section of this document.

**1.**    **Personal Information We Collect**

We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or household ("**personal information**").

In the last twelve months, we have collected the following categories of personal information from consumers:

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Category** | **Examples** | **Collected** | **Disclosed** |
| **Identifiers** | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, Social Security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers. | YES | YES |
| **Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute.** | A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information.<br><br>Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | YES | YES |
| **Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.** | Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information). | NO  | NO  |
| **Commercial information.** | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | NO  | NO  |
| **Biometric information.** | Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data. | NO  | NO  |
| **Internet or other similar network activity.** | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. | YES | YES |
| **Geolocation data.** | Physical location or movements. | YES | YES |
| **Sensory data.** | Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information. | NO  | NO  |
| **Professional or employment-related information.** | Current or past job history or performance evaluations. | NO  | NO  |
| **Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act).** | Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. | NO  | NO  |
| **Inferences drawn from other personal information.** | Profile reflecting a person’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | NO  | NO  |
| **Sensitive Personal Information.** | (1) Social Security number, driver’s license number, state identification number, passport number; (2) account log-in, financial account, debit card, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account; (3) precise geolocation information; (4) racial or ethnic origin, religious, or philosophical believes, or union membership; (5) contents of mail, email, and text messages unless the business is the intended recipient of the communication; (6) genetic data; (7) biometric data for the purposes of uniquely identifying a consumer; (8) health information; (9) sex life or sexual orientation information. | YES | YES |

We obtain this information from the various categories of sources:

·       Directly from you. For example, from the webform you create an online account.

·       Indirectly from you. For example, from observing your interactions on our website.

**2.**    **How We Use, Disclose, Share, and Sell Information We Collect.**

Please read the [Privacy](#_[COMPANY]_PRIVACY_NOTICE) Policy to learn how we use, disclose, share, and sell personal information we collect.

**3.**    **Your Rights.**

A.     Right to Access and Data Portability

You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will disclose to you:

·       The categories of personal information we collected about you.

·       The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.

·       Our business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling, or sharing the personal information.

·       The categories of third parties with whom we disclose that personal information.

·       The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).

·       Whether we sold, shared, or otherwise disclosed your personal information for a business purpose.

B.     Right to Delete

You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies. We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us to:

·       Complete the transaction for which we collected the information.

·       Provide a good or service that you requested.

·       Take actions reasonably anticipated, given our ongoing business relationship.

·       Fulfill a written warranty or product recall conducted under federal law.

·       Perform our contract with you.

·       Protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity.

·       Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing functionality.

·       Exercise free speech or ensure that other consumers may exercise their free speech.

·       Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act.

·       Engage in public or peer-reviewed public interest research if deletion may seriously impair the research’s achievement and if you previously provided informed consent.

·       Use the information internally, as reasonably expected by consumers.

·       Use the information internally, compatible with the law and context you provided it.

·       Comply with a legal obligation.

C.     Right to Correct

You have the right to request that we correct inaccurate personal information, taking into account the nature of the personal information and the purposes for processing the personal information. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to correct the inaccurate personal information.

D.    Right to Non-Discrimination

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of these rights. Unless permitted by California law, we will not:

·       Deny you goods or services.

·       Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.

·       Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including granting discounts or benefits, or imposing penalties.

·       Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.

However, we may offer you certain financial incentives permitted by California law that can result in different prices, rates, or quality levels. Any permissible financial incentive we offer will reasonably relate to your personal information’s value and contain written terms that describe the program’s material aspects. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior affirmative consent, which you may revoke at any time.

E.     Right to Opt Out of the Sale of Personal Information

Company does not sell personal information.

F.     Right to Opt Out of Sharing Personal Information for Personalized Advertising

Company shares personal information for cross-context behavioral advertising. You may opt out of this sharing, please follow the instructions provided in the "[Exercising Your Rights](#_Exercising_Your_Rights)" section of this document.

G.     Right to Limit the Processing of Sensitive Personal Information

Company does not process sensitive personal information beyond what is necessary to perform the services or provide the goods reasonably expected by an average consumer who requests those goods or services.

H.    Rights Under California's "Shine the Light" Law

California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits California residents that use our website to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

European Union, United Kingdom, and India
-----------------------------------------

Last Updated: March 25th, 2024

This supplemental privacy policy provides European Economic Area ("EEA"), United Kingdom (“UK”), and Indian residents additional information required by applicable data privacy laws. These provisions, together with the statements in the above general Privacy Policy, set forth our practices with respect to EEA, UK, and Indian personal data. For residents of these jurisdictions, if there is a conflict between this supplement and the Privacy Policy, this supplement governs.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

A.     Contact information:

Data Protection Officer:        Shailen Banker
----------------------------------------------

Email:                                     [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Address:                                 3020 Lindenwood Dr.
------------------------------------------------------------

Dearborn, Michigan 48120
------------------------

B.     Legal bases and purposes for data processing:

We only process personal information when we have a legal basis for the processing or have your consent to do so. Specifically, we will only process your personal information in connection with one or more of the following bases:
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                With your consent. 
------------------------------------

•                For the reason you provided it to us.
------------------------------------------------------

•                To satisfy an applicable legal requirement. 
-------------------------------------------------------------

•                To serve the public interest, such as processing in response to a governmental request. 
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

C.     Automated decision making and profiling:

We do not make automated decisions about you or engage in data profiling.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------

D.    Personal information requirements:

To engage with our services and Website, you may be required to provide certain personal information to enable us to perform the services. Over the course of your relationship with Intelilinks, you will be provided with information regarding which data elements are required.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

In addition, when Intelilinks provides its services or acts as a data processor, we may receive your personal information from third parties as needed to provide our services. If Intelilinks is processing your personal information as a data processor, we will refer you to our client for assistance with these requests. We support our clients with responding to requests as required by law.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

You may also decline our marketing communications.
--------------------------------------------------

If you believe that we have violated applicable law in our processing of your personal information, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or contact a supervisory authority.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

E.     Your rights:

As a resident of the EEA, UK, or India, you have choices regarding how we use your personal information. You are entitled to:
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                The right to access: You have the right to request copies of your personal information.  We may charge you a minor fee for this service.
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                The right to rectification: You have the right to request that we correct any information that you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request that we complete information that you believe is incomplete.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                The right to erasure: You have the right to request that we erase your personal information under certain conditions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                The right to object to processing: You have the right to object to our processing of your personal information, under certain conditions.
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                The right to data portability: You have the right to request that we transfer the data we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

•                You may also decline our marketing communications.
-------------------------------------------------------------------

To exercise these rights, please contact us at the e-mail or mailing address above. Note that for your protection, we may need to verify your identity before we can process your request.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

If you believe that we have violated applicable law in our processing of your personal information, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or contact a supervisory authority.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

F.     International Transfers:

Our company is based in the United States.  Your personal information may be transferred to, stored at, or processed in the United States, or other countries that may not have equivalent privacy or data protection laws.  By using our Website and/or services, you understand and agree to these processing terms. 
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

G.     Data Retention:

Your personal information will be retained for as long as the information is needed for the purposes set forth in our Privacy Policy and this supplement, as well as for any additional period that may be required or permitted by law. The retention period depends on the purpose(s) for which the data was collected, how it is used, and applicable law. If we do not have a legal basis for retaining your information, we will delete it as required by applicable law.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Exercising Your Rights
----------------------

Depending on where you live, the rights described in this supplement may apply to you. To exercise your rights compatible with applicable law, please submit a verifiable consumer request at [\[email protected\]](https://www.lyrarc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). 

A.    Verifiable Consumer Requests

Your verifiable consumer request must provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected information, and describe your request in sufficient detail that allows us to properly respond to it. We cannot respond to your request if we cannot verify your identity and confirm that the information relates to you.

Only you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child. To designate an authorized agent, please contact us via the methods noted above. If you are a California resident, you can designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf only if: (1) the authorized agent is a natural person or a business entity registered with the Secretary of State of California; and (2) you sign a written declaration that you authorize the authorized agent to act on your behalf.  If you use an authorized agent under California law to submit a request to exercise your rights, please have the authorized agent take the following steps in addition to the steps described above:

·      Mail a copy of your signed written declaration authorizing the authorized agent to act on your behalf; and

·      Provide any information we request in our response to your email to verify your identity. The information requested will depend on your prior interactions with us and the sensitivity of the personal information at issue.

If you provide an authorized agent with power of attorney pursuant to California Probate Code sections 4121 to 4130, it may not be necessary to perform these steps and we will respond to any request from such authorized agent in accordance with the CCPA.

California residents may make a verifiable consumer request twice within a 12-month period, free of charge, unless the request is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.  

B.    Response Time

We will respond to verifiable consumer requests within the time allotted under applicable law, generally forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time (up to 45 days), we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing in compliance with applicable law.

C.     Response Content

Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable consumer request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance in compliance with applicable law.

D.    Method of Response

You do not need to create an account with us to make a verifiable consumer request. However, if you have an account with us, we will deliver our written response to that account. If you do not have an account with us, we will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.

Support LyrArc

We took a different way to help millions around the world build educated informed mindsets that affects and shapes their lives. For a future that is open, global and digital, with everyone having access to high quality information. We believe in the renewal of America, renewal of Europe, the renewal of India, the rest of Asia, Latin America and Africa. The renewal of our supply chains, health, education, infrastructure, as we rebuild our countries after the pandemic. Literacy and knowledge we believe cannot thrive and grow in a world of web bots, web crawlers, or AI. This requires human curiosity, human learning, and human imagination. We take as inspiration the saying- “One has to be free, and as broad as sky. One has to have a mind that is crystal clear, only then can truth shine in it.” Every contribution whether big or small is precious- in this crisis and ahead.

Copyright © 2006 - 2024 Intelilinks LLC  

Support LyrArc

Reader contributions keep LyrArc open for everyone

* * *

* * *

###### Updated December 10

* * *

#### Top Stories

* * *

#### Browse Lyrarc's

* * *

#### LyrArc Insights

* * *

#### **Countries**

#### **Business**

#### **Society**

#### **Worklife Balance**

### Personalize LyrArc

Sign up to personalize your feed of topics and articles.

or

Lyrarc.com is about the gift of knowledge to help create educated and informed mindsets that can shape better lives and better societies. Cookies we use are minimal needed for site to work. To keep it secure and reliable with Cloudflare, to reach you with Google Search Microsoft Search, to provide what you are looking for using Google Analytics and Microsoft Clarity, and Google Translate for use in your language. To provide you with the best possible experience.

Accept Reject
